https://checkout.shopify.com/5060065/policies/1505463

<h1>PROTECTING YOUR PRIVACY</h1>
<p>FGM UK Ltd trading as FairyGothMother</p>
<h2>1. Introduction</h2>
<p>This Privacy Notice explains in detail the types of personal data we may collect about you when you interact with us. It also explains how we’ll store and handle that data, and keep it safe.</p>
<p>We know that there’s a lot of information here but we want you to be fully informed about your rights, and how FairyGothMother uses your data.</p>
<p>We hope the following will answer many of the questions you may have but if not, please do get in touch with us.</p>
<p>Over time this Privacy Notice will change. Any significant changes wil be notified to you, but you’re welcome to come back and check it whenever you wish.</p>
<p>When using the FairyGothMother website, FGM UK Ltd is the data controller.</p>
<h2>2. This Privacy Notice</h2>
<p>It applies to both United Kingdom and international orders. <br />For simplicity throughout this notice, ‘we’ and ‘us’ means FGM UK Ltd trading as FairyGothMother.</p>
<h2>3. Explaining the legal bases we rely on.</h2>
<p>The law on data protection sets out a number of different reasons for which a company may collect and process your personal data, including:</p>
<p>Consent -</p>
<p>In specific situations, we can collect and process your data with your consent.</p>
<p>e.g. when you tick a box to receive email newsletters.</p>
<p>When collecting your personal data, we’ll always make clear to you which data is necessary in connection with a particular service.</p>
<p>Contractual obligations -</p>
<p>In certain circumstances, we need your personal data to comply with our contractual obligations.</p>
<p>e.g. if you order an item from us for home delivery, we’ll collect your address details to deliver your purchase, and pass them to our courier.</p>
<p>Legal compliance -</p>
<p>If the law requires us to, we may need to collect and process your data.</p>
<p>e.g. we can pass on details of people involved in fraud or other criminal activity affecting the Partnership to law enforcement.</p>
<p>Legitimate interest -</p>
<p>In specific situations, we require your data to pursue our legitimate interests in a way which might reasonably be expected as part of running our business and which does not materially impact your rights, freedom or interests.</p>
<p>e.g. we will use your purchase history to send you or make available personalised offers, if you have opted in for such contact.</p>
<p>We also combine the shopping history of many customers to identify trends and ensure we can keep up with demand, or develop new products/services.</p>
<h2>4. When do we collect your personal data?</h2>
<p>When you visit our websites, and use your account to buy products and services, or redeem vouchers from us on the phone, in our studio or online. <br />When you make an online purchase and check out as a guest (in which case we just collect transaction-based data). <br />When you create an account with us. <br />When you purchase a product or service in store or by phone but don’t have (or don’t use) an account. <br />When you contact us by any means with queries, complaints etc. <br />When you enter prize draws or competitions. <br />When you book any kind of appointment with us or book to attend an event, e.g. a Sample Sale appointment. <br />When you choose to complete any surveys we send you. <br />When you fill in any forms. For example, if an accident happens in store, we may collect your personal data. <br />When you’ve given a third party permission to share with us the information they hold about you.</p>
<h2>5. What sort of personal data do we collect?</h2>
<p>If you have an online account with us: your name, billing/delivery address, orders and receipts, email and telephone number. For your security, we’ll also keep an encrypted record of your login password.</p>
<p>Details of your interactions with us in our studio or online.</p>
<p>e.g. we collect notes from our conversations with you at appointments</p>
<p>We’ll only ask for and use your personal data collected for recommending items of interest and to tailor your shopping experience with us. Of course, it’s always your choice whether you share such details with us. <br />Payment card information. <br />Your comments and product reviews.</p>
<h2>6. How and why do we use your personal data?</h2>
<p>We want to give you the best possible customer experience.</p>
<p>Of course, if you wish to change how we use your data, you’ll find details in the ‘What are my rights?’ section below.</p>
<p>Remember, if you choose not to share your personal data with us, or refuse certain contact permissions, we might not be able to provide some services you’ve asked for.</p>
<p>e.g. if you’ve asked us to let you know when an item comes back into stock, we can’t do that if you’ve withdrawn your general consent to hear from us.</p>
<p>Here’s how we’ll use your personal data and why:</p>
<p>To process any orders that you make by using our website or in store. If we don’t collect your personal data during checkout, we won’t be able to process your order and comply with our legal obligations.</p>
<p>e.g. your details will need to be passed to our third party Payment Gateway supplier, SagePay, so they can process your order payment, and we may keep your details for a reasonable period afterwards in order to fulfil any contractual obligations such as refunds, guarantees and so on.</p>
<p>To respond to your queries, refund requests and complaints. Handling the information you sent enables us to respond. We may also keep a record of these to inform any future communication with us and to demonstrate how we communicated with you throughout. We do this on the basis of our contractual obligations to you, our legal obligations and our legitimate interests in providing you with the best service and understanding how we can improve our service based on your experience.</p>
<p>To protect our business and your account from fraud and other illegal activities. This includes using your personal data to maintain, update and safeguard your account. We’ll also monitor your browsing activity with us to quickly identify and resolve any problems and protect the integrity of our website. We’ll do all of this as part of our legitimate interest. <br /> e.g. by checking your password when you login and using automated monitoring of IP addresses to identify possible fraudulent logins from unexpected locations.</p>
<p>To process payments and to prevent fraudulent transactions. We do this on the basis of our legitimate business interests. This also helps to protect our customers from fraud. <br />If we discover any criminal activity or alleged criminal activity through our use of fraud monitoring and suspicious transaction monitoring, we will process this data for the purposes of preventing or detecting unlawful acts. We aim to protect the individuals we interact with from criminal activities.</p>
<p>With your consent, we will use your personal data, to keep you informed by email, web, text, and telephone about relevant products and services including tailored special offers, discounts, promotions, events, competitions and so on.</p>
<p>Of course, you are free to opt out of hearing from us by any of these channels at any time.</p>
<p>You are free to opt out of hearing from us by post at any time.</p>
<p>To send you communications required by law or which are necessary to inform you about our changes to the services we provide you. For example, updates to this Privacy Notice, product recall notices, and legally required information relating to your orders. These service messages will not include any promotional content and do not require prior consent when sent by email or text message. If we do not use your personal data for these purposes, we would be unable to comply with our legal obligations.</p>
<p>To display the most interesting content to you on our website, we’ll use data we hold about your favourite brands or products and so on. We do so on the basis of your consent for our website to place cookies or similar technology on your device.</p>
<p>To administer any of our prize draws or competitions which you enter, based on your consent given at the time of entering.</p>
<p>To comply with our contractual or legal obligations to share data with law enforcement. <br /> e.g. when a court order is submitted to share data with law enforcement agencies or a court of law.</p>
<p>To send you survey and feedback requests to help improve our services. These messages will not include any promotional content and do not require prior consent when sent by email or text message. We have a legitimate interest to do so as this helps make our products or services more relevant to you.</p>
<p>Of course, you are free to opt out of receiving these requests from us at any time by contacting us.</p>
<p>To process your booking/appointment requests.</p>
<p>Sometimes, we’ll need to share your details with a third party who is providing a service (such as delivery couriers). Without sharing your personal data, we’d be unable to fulfil your request.</p>
<h2>7. Personalised direct marketing</h2>
<p>We will only use the data we have collected about you. We do not combine with any third party's data.</p>
<h2>8. How we protect your personal data</h2>
<p>We know how much data security matters to all our customers. With this in mind we will treat your data with the utmost care and take all appropriate steps to protect it.</p>
<p>We secure access to all transactional areas of our website using ‘https’ technology.</p>
<p>Access to your personal data is password-protected. Payments and payment card information is not held by us, but by our supplier Payment Handlers, Shopify and Global Payments Inc., both of whom comply with the Global Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).</p>
<p>Our website online processes, such as customer orders, is hosted by Shopify in the USA and Canada, which holds the the data we collect on their servers in those countries.</p>
<h2>9. How long will we keep your personal data?h2<br />Whenever we collect or process your personal data, we’ll only keep it for as long as is necessary for the purpose for which it was collected.</h2>
<p>At the end of that retention period, your data will either be deleted completely or anonymised, e.g. by aggregation with other data so that it can be used in a non-identifiable way for statistical analysis and business planning.</p>
<p>Some examples of customer data retention periods:</p>
<p>Orders <br />When you place an order, we’ll keep the personal data you give us for five years so we can comply with our legal and contractual obligations.</p>
<p>Inactive accounts <br />If you’ve not used your account for more than five years, we’ll close the account and delete or anonymise the personal data associated with it.</p>
<h2>10. Who do we share your personal data with?</h2>
<p>We sometimes share your personal data with trusted third parties.</p>
<p>e.g. delivery couriers, for fraud management, our payment providers.</p>
<p>Here’s the policy we apply to those organisations to keep your data safe and protect your privacy:</p>
<p>We provide only the information they need to perform their specific services. <br />They may only use your data for the exact purposes we specify in our contract with them. <br />If we stop using their services, any of your data held by them will either be deleted or rendered anonymous. <br />Examples of the kind of third parties we work with are:</p>
<p>IT companies who support our website and other business systems. <br />Operational companies such as delivery couriers. Payment Gateway companies.</p>
<p>For fraud management, we may share information about fraudulent or potentially fraudulent activity in our premises or systems. This may include sharing data about individuals with law enforcement bodies. <br />We may also be required to disclose your personal data to the police or other enforcement, regulatory or Government body, in your country of origin or elsewhere, upon a valid request to do so. These requests are assessed on a case-by-case basis and take the privacy of our customers into consideration. <br />We may sell the FairyGothMother at some point in the future and this will involve the transfer of the whole business to new owners. If this happens, your personal data will, where relevant, be transferred to the new owner or controlling party, under the terms of this Privacy Notice.</p>
<p>For further information please contact our Data Protection Officer.</p>
<h2>11. Where your personal data may be processed</h2>
<br />Sometimes we will need to share your personal data with third parties and suppliers outside the European Economic Area (EEA).
<p>International orders</p>
<p>If you are based outside the UK and place an order with us, the personal data that we collect from you will be held on Shopify's data servers in Canada and the USA.</p>
<p>Protecting your data outside the EEA</p>
<p>The EEA includes all EU Member countries as well as Iceland, Liechtenstein and Norway.</p>
<p>We may transfer personal data that we collect from you to third-party data processors in countries that are outside the EEA such as Canada or the USA.</p>
<p>If we do this, we have procedures in place to ensure your data receives the same protection as if it were being processed inside the EEA. For example, our contracts with third parties stipulate the standards they must follow at all times. If you wish for more information about these contracts please contact our Data Protection Officer.</p>
<p>Any transfer of your personal data will follow applicable laws and we will treat the information under the guiding principles of this Privacy Notice.</p>
<h2>12. What are your rights over your personal data?</h2>
<p>An overview of your different rights</p>
<p>You have the right to request:</p>
<p>Access to the personal data we hold about you. <br />The correction of your personal data when incorrect, out of date or incomplete. <br />That we stop using your personal data for direct marketing. <br />That we stop any consent-based processing of your personal data after you withdraw that consent. <br />You can contact us to request to exercise these rights at any time as follows:</p>
<p>To ask for your information please contact The Data Protection Officer, FGM UK Ltd, 11A Evelyn Court, Grinstead Road, London SE8 5AD or email gdpr@fairygothmother.co.uk To ask for your information to be amended please contact us.</p>
<p>If we choose not to action your request we will explain to you the reasons for our refusal.</p>
<p>Your right to withdraw consent</p>
<p>Whenever you have given us your consent to use your personal data, you have the right to change your mind at any time and withdraw that consent.</p>
<p>Where we rely on our legitimate interest</p>
<p>In cases where we are processing your personal data on the basis of our legitimate interest, you can ask us to stop for reasons connected to your individual situation.</p>
<p>We must then do so unless we believe we have a legitimate overriding reason to continue processing your personal data.</p>
<p>Direct marketing</p>
<p>You have the right to stop the use of your personal data for direct marketing activity. We must always comply with your request.</p>
<p>Checking your identity</p>
<p>To protect the confidentiality of your information, we will ask you to verify your identity before proceeding with any request you make under this Privacy Notice.</p>
<p>If you have authorised a third party to submit a request on your behalf, we will ask them to prove they have your permission to act.</p>
<h2>13. Contacting the Regulator</h2>
<p>If you feel that your data has not been handled correctly, or you are unhappy with our response to any requests you have made to us regarding the use of your personal data, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office.</p>
<p>You can contact them by calling 0303 123 1113.</p>
<p>Or go online to www.ico.org.uk/concerns (please note we can't be responsible for the content of external websites)</p>
<p>If you are based outside the UK, you have the right to lodge your complaint with the relevant data protection regulator in your country of residence. Details can be found in Section 14.</p>
<h2>14. If you live outside the UK</h2>
<p>For all non-UK customers</p>
<p>By using our services or providing your personal data to us, you expressly consent to the processing of your personal data by us or on our behalf. Of course, you still have the right to ask us not to process your data in certain ways, and if you do so, we will respect your wishes.</p>
<p>Sometimes we’ll need to transfer your personal data between countries to enable us to supply the goods or services you’ve requested.</p>
<p>By dealing with us, you are giving your consent to this overseas use, transfer and disclosure of your personal data outside your country of residence for our ordinary business purposes.</p>
<p>This may occur because our information technology storage facilities and servers are located outside your country of residence, and could include storage of your personal data on servers in the UK.</p>
<p>We’ll ensure that reasonable steps are taken to prevent third parties outside your country of residence using your personal data in any way that’s not set out in this Privacy Notice. We’ll also make sure we adequately protect the confidentiality and privacy of your personal data.</p>
<p>We’ll ensure that any third parties process your personal data only in accordance with their legitimate interests. These third parties may be subject to different laws from those which apply in your country of residence. Please note that we do not take active steps to ensure that any overseas recipient of your personal data complies with the laws which apply in your country.</p>
<h2>15. Any questions?</h2>
<p>We hope this Privacy Notice has been helpful in setting out the way we handle your personal data and your rights to control it.</p>
<p>If you have any questions that haven’t been covered here, please contact our Data Protection Officer who will be pleased to help you:</p>
<p>Email us on GDPR@fairygothmother.co.uk <br />Or write to us at <br />Data Protection Officer <br />FGM UK Ltd <br />11A Evelyn Court <br />Grinstead Road <br />London SE8 5AD</p>
<p>This notice was last updated on 9/06/2020</p>
Opens external website in a new window.
Opens in a new window.
Opens external website.
Customer information - FairyGothMother - Checkout
